<ruleset name="CCC"
         xmlns="http://pmd.sourceforge.net/ruleset/2.0.0"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://pmd.sourceforge.net/ruleset/2.0.0 http://pmd.sourceforge.net/ruleset_2_0_0.xsd">
    <description>
        CCC PMD Rules.  This is based on rules for 5.3.2.
    </description>

    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/FieldNamingConventions">
        <description>
            Configurable naming conventions for field declarations. This rule reports variable declarations
            which do not match the regex that applies to their specific kind —e.g. constants (static final),
            enum constant, final field. Each regex can be configured through properties.

            By default this rule uses the standard Java naming convention (Camel case), and uses the ALL_UPPER
            convention for constants and enum constants.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
        <properties>
            <property name="enumConstantPattern" value="[A-Z][a-zA-Z_0-9]*"/>
        </properties>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/FormalParameterNamingConventions">
        <description>
            Configurable naming conventions for formal parameters of methods and lambdas. This rule reports
            formal parameters which do not match the regex that applies to their specific kind (e.g. lambda
            parameter, or final formal parameter). Each regex can be configured through properties.

            By default this rule uses the standard Java naming convention (Camel case).
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/LocalVariableNamingConventions">
        <description>
            Configurable naming conventions for local variable declarations and other locally-scoped
            variables. This rule reports variable declarations which do not match the regex that applies
            to their specific kind (e.g. final variable, or catch-clause parameter). Each regex can be
            configured through properties.

            By default this rule uses the standard Java naming convention (Camel case).
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/AccessorMethodGeneration">
        <description>
            When accessing a private field / method from another class, the Java compiler will generate an
            accessor methods with package-private visibility. This adds overhead, and to the dex method count
            on Android. This situation can be avoided by changing the visibility of the field / method from
            private to package-private.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/AvoidReassigningParameters">
        <description>
            Reassigning values to incoming parameters is not recommended. Use temporary local variables instead.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/ForLoopCanBeForeach">
        <description>
            Reports loops that can be safely replaced with the foreach syntax. The rule considers loops over lists,
            arrays and iterators. A loop is safe to replace if it only uses the index variable to access an element
            of the list or array, only has one update statement, and loops through every element of the list or array
            left to right.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/MissingOverride">
        <description>
            Annotating overridden methods with @Override ensures at compile time that the method really overrides
            one, which helps refactoring and clarifies intent.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UseCollectionIsEmpty">
        <description>
            The isEmpty() method on java.util.Collection is provided to determine if a collection has any
            elements. Comparing the value of size() to 0 does not convey intent as well as the isEmpty() method.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UseVarargs">
        <description>
            Java 5 introduced the varargs parameter declaration for methods and constructors. This syntactic
            sugar provides flexibility for users of these methods and constructors, allowing them to avoid
            having to deal with the creation of an array.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>

    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/JumbledIncrementer">
        <description>
            Avoid jumbled loop incrementers - its usually a mistake, and is confusing even if intentional.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/ForLoopShouldBeWhileLoop">
        <description>
            Some for loops can be simplified to while loops, this makes them more concise.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/OverrideBothEqualsAndHashcode">
        <description>
            Override both public boolean Object.equals(Object other), and public int Object.hashCode(), or override neither.  Even if you are inheriting a hashCode() from a parent class, consider implementing hashCode and explicitly delegating to your superclass.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/multithreading.xml/DoubleCheckedLocking">
        <description>
            Partially created objects can be returned by the Double Checked Locking pattern when used in Java.
            An optimizing JRE may assign a reference to the baz variable before it creates the object the
            reference is intended to point to.

            For more details refer to: http://www.javaworld.com/javaworld/jw-02-2001/jw-0209-double.html
            or http://www.cs.umd.edu/~pugh/java/memoryModel/DoubleCheckedLocking.html
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/ReturnFromFinallyBlock">
        <description>
            Avoid returning from a finally block, this can discard exceptions.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UnconditionalIfStatement">
        <description>
            Do not use "if" statements whose conditionals are always true or always false.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/BooleanInstantiation">
        <description>
            Avoid instantiating Boolean objects; you can reference Boolean.TRUE, Boolean.FALSE, or call Boolean.valueOf() instead.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/ClassCastExceptionWithToArray">
        <description>
            When deriving an array of a specific class from your Collection, one should provide an array of
            the same class as the parameter of the toArray() method. Doing otherwise you will will result
            in a ClassCastException.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidDecimalLiteralsInBigDecimalConstructor">
        <description>
            One might assume that the result of "new BigDecimal(0.1)" is exactly equal to 0.1, but it is actually
            equal to .1000000000000000055511151231257827021181583404541015625.
            This is because 0.1 cannot be represented exactly as a double (or as a binary fraction of any finite
            length). Thus, the long value that is being passed in to the constructor is not exactly equal to 0.1,
            appearances notwithstanding.

            The (String) constructor, on the other hand, is perfectly predictable: 'new BigDecimal("0.1")' is
            exactly equal to 0.1, as one would expect.  Therefore, it is generally recommended that the
            (String) constructor be used in preference to this one.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/MisplacedNullCheck">
        <description>
            The null check here is misplaced. If the variable is null a NullPointerException will be thrown.
            Either the check is useless (the variable will never be "null") or it is incorrect.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/multithreading.xml/AvoidThreadGroup">
        <description>
            Avoid using java.lang.ThreadGroup; although it is intended to be used in a threaded environment
            it contains methods that are not thread-safe.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/BrokenNullCheck">
        <description>
            The null check is broken since it will throw a NullPointerException itself.
            It is likely that you used || instead of &amp;&amp; or vice versa.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/BigIntegerInstantiation">
        <description>
            Don't create instances of already existing BigInteger (BigInteger.ZERO, BigInteger.ONE) and
            for Java 1.5 onwards, BigInteger.TEN and BigDecimal (BigDecimal.ZERO, BigDecimal.ONE, BigDecimal.TEN)
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidUsingOctalValues">
        <description>

            Integer literals should not start with zero since this denotes that the rest of literal will be
            interpreted as an octal value.

        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidMultipleUnaryOperators">
        <description>

            The use of multiple unary operators may be problematic, and/or confusing.
            Ensure that the intended usage is not a bug, or consider simplifying the expression.

        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/ExtendsObject">
        <description>No need to explicitly extend Object.</description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/CheckSkipResult">
        <description>The skip() method may skip a smaller number of bytes than requested. Check the returned value to find out if it was the case or not.</description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidBranchingStatementAsLastInLoop">
        <description>

            Using a branching statement as the last part of a loop may be a bug, and/or is confusing.
            Ensure that the usage is not a bug, or consider using another approach.

        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/multithreading.xml/DontCallThreadRun">
        <description>
            Explicitly calling Thread.run() method will execute in the caller's thread of control.  Instead, call Thread.start() for the intended behavior.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/DontUseFloatTypeForLoopIndices">
        <description>
            Don't use floating point for loop indices. If you must use floating point, use double
            unless you're certain that float provides enough precision and you have a compelling
            performance need (space or time).
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AssignmentInOperand">
        <description>
            Avoid assignments in operands; this can make code more complicated and harder to read.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/DontImportSun">
        <description>
            Avoid importing anything from the 'sun.*' packages.  These packages are not portable and are likely to change.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/SuspiciousOctalEscape">
        <description>
            A suspicious octal escape sequence was found inside a String literal.
            The Java language specification (section 3.10.6) says an octal
            escape sequence inside a literal String shall consist of a backslash
            followed by:

            OctalDigit | OctalDigit OctalDigit | ZeroToThree OctalDigit OctalDigit

            Any octal escape sequence followed by non-octal digits can be confusing,
            e.g. "\038" is interpreted as the octal escape sequence "\03" followed by
            the literal character "8".
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/DefaultPackage">
        <description>
            Use explicit scoping instead of the default package private level.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/AvoidUsingShortType">
        <description>

            Java uses the 'short' type to reduce memory usage, not to optimize calculation. In fact, the JVM does not have any
            arithmetic capabilities for the short type: the JVM must convert the short into an int, do the proper calculation
            and convert the int back to a short. Thus any storage gains found through use of the 'short' type may be offset by
            adverse impacts on performance.

        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/AvoidUsingNativeCode">
        <description>

            Unnecessary reliance on Java Native Interface (JNI) calls directly reduces application portability
            and increases the maintenance burden.

        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/DoNotCallGarbageCollectionExplicitly">
        <description>

            Calls to System.gc(), Runtime.getRuntime().gc(), and System.runFinalization() are not advised. Code should have the
            same behavior whether the garbage collection is disabled using the option -Xdisableexplicitgc or not.
            Moreover, "modern" jvms do a very good job handling garbage collections. If memory usage issues unrelated to memory
            leaks develop within an application, it should be dealt with JVM options rather than within the code itself.

        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/OneDeclarationPerLine">
        <description>

            Java allows the use of several variables declaration of the same type on one line. However, it
            can lead to quite messy code. This rule looks for several declarations on the same line.

        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <!--<rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/AvoidPrefixingMethodParameters">-->
        <!--<description>-->

            <!--Prefixing parameters by 'in' or 'out' pollutes the name of the parameters and reduces code readability.-->
            <!--To indicate whether or not a parameter will be modify in a method, its better to document method-->
            <!--behavior with Javadoc.-->

        <!--</description>-->
        <!--<priority>4</priority>-->
    <!--</rule>-->
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidLiteralsInIfCondition">
        <description>
            Avoid using hard-coded literals in conditional statements. By declaring them as static variables
            or private members with descriptive names maintainability is enhanced. By default, the literals "-1" and "0" are ignored.
            More exceptions can be defined with the property "ignoreMagicNumbers".
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/ExcessiveImports">
        <description>
            A high number of imports can indicate a high degree of coupling within an object. This rule
            counts the number of unique imports and reports a violation if the count is above the
            user-specified threshold.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/LooseCoupling">
        <description>
            The use of implementation types as object references limits your ability to use alternate
            implementations in the future as requirements change. Whenever available, referencing objects
            by their interface types provides much more flexibility.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/UseUtilityClass">
        <description>

            For classes that only have static methods, consider making them utility classes.
            Note that this doesn't apply to abstract classes, since their subclasses may
            well include non-static methods.  Also, if you want this class to be a utility class,
            remember to add a private constructor to prevent instantiation.
            (Note, that this use was known before PMD 5.1.0 as UseSingleton).

        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SimplifyBooleanReturns">
        <description>
            Avoid unnecessary if-then-else statements when returning a boolean. The result of
            the conditional test can be returned instead.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SimplifyBooleanExpressions">
        <description>
            Avoid unnecessary comparisons in boolean expressions, they serve no purpose and impacts readability.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/SwitchStmtsShouldHaveDefault">
        <description>
            All switch statements should include a default option to catch any unspecified values.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SwitchDensity">
        <description>
            A high ratio of statements to labels in a switch statement implies that the switch statement
            is overloaded.  Consider moving the statements into new methods or creating subclasses based
            on the switch variable.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/ConstructorCallsOverridableMethod">
        <description>
            Calling overridable methods during construction poses a risk of invoking methods on an incompletely
            constructed object and can be difficult to debug.
            It may leave the sub-class unable to construct its superclass or forced to replicate the construction
            process completely within itself, losing the ability to call super().  If the default constructor
            contains a call to an overridable method, the subclass may be completely uninstantiable.   Note that
            this includes method calls throughout the control flow graph - i.e., if a constructor Foo() calls a
            private method bar() that calls a public method buz(), this denotes a problem.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/AccessorClassGeneration">
        <description>
            Instantiation by way of private constructors from outside of the constructor's class often causes the
            generation of an accessor. A factory method, or non-privatization of the constructor can eliminate this
            situation. The generated class file is actually an interface.  It gives the accessing class the ability
            to invoke a new hidden package scope constructor that takes the interface as a supplementary parameter.
            This turns a private constructor effectively into one with package scope, and is challenging to discern.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/FinalFieldCouldBeStatic">
        <description>
            If a final field is assigned to a compile-time constant, it could be made static, thus saving overhead
            in each object at runtime.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/CloseResource">
        <description>
            Ensure that resources (like Connection, Statement, and ResultSet objects) are always closed after use.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
        <properties>
            <property name="types" value="Connection, Statement, PreparedStatement, ResultSet"/>
            <property name="closeTargets" value="JdbcUtils.closeResultSet,JdbcUtils.closeStatement,JdbcUtils.closeConnection,DbUtils.closeQuietly,close"/>
        </properties>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/NonStaticInitializer">
        <description>
            A non-static initializer block will be called any time a constructor is invoked (just prior to
            invoking the constructor).  While this is a valid language construct, it is rarely used and is
            confusing.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/DefaultLabelNotLastInSwitchStmt">
        <description>
            By convention, the default label should be the last label in a switch statement.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/NonCaseLabelInSwitchStatement">
        <description>
            A non-case label (e.g. a named break/continue label) was present in a switch statement.
            This legal, but confusing. It is easy to mix up the case labels and the non-case labels.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/OptimizableToArrayCall">
        <description>
            Calls to a collection's toArray() method should specify target arrays sized to match the size of the
            collection. Initial arrays that are too small are discarded in favour of new ones that have to be created
            that are the proper size.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/BadComparison">
        <description>
            Avoid equality comparisons with Double.NaN. Due to the implicit lack of representation
            precision when comparing floating point numbers these are likely to cause logic errors.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/EqualsNull">
        <description>
            Tests for null should not use the equals() method. The '==' operator should be used instead.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/ConfusingTernary">
        <description>
            Avoid negation within an "if" expression with an "else" clause.  For example, rephrase:

            if (x != y) diff(); else same();
            as:
            if (x == y) same(); else diff();

            Most "if (x != y)" cases without an "else" are often return cases, so consistent use of this
            rule makes the code easier to read.  Also, this resolves trivial ordering problems, such
            as "does the error case go first?" or "does the common case go first?".
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/InstantiationToGetClass">
        <description>
            Avoid instantiating an object just to call getClass() on it; use the .class public member instead.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/IdempotentOperations">
        <description>
            Avoid idempotent operations - they have no effect.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/SimpleDateFormatNeedsLocale">
        <description>
            Be sure to specify a Locale when creating SimpleDateFormat instances to ensure that locale-appropriate
            formatting is used.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/AvoidProtectedFieldInFinalClass">
        <description>
            Do not use protected fields in final classes since they cannot be subclassed.
            Clarify your intent by using private or package access modifiers instead.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AssignmentToNonFinalStatic">
        <description>
            Identifies a possible unsafe usage of a static field.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/MissingStaticMethodInNonInstantiatableClass">
        <description>
            A class that has private constructors and does not have any static methods or fields cannot be used.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/multithreading.xml/AvoidSynchronizedAtMethodLevel">
        <description>
            Method-level synchronization can cause problems when new code is added to the method.
            Block-level synchronization helps to ensure that only the code that needs synchronization
            gets it.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/MissingBreakInSwitch">
        <description>
            Switch statements without break or return statements for each case option
            may indicate problematic behaviour. Empty cases are ignored as these indicate an intentional fall-through.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/multithreading.xml/UseNotifyAllInsteadOfNotify">
        <description>
            Thread.notify() awakens a thread monitoring the object. If more than one thread is monitoring, then only
            one is chosen.  The thread chosen is arbitrary; thus its usually safer to call notifyAll() instead.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidInstanceofChecksInCatchClause">
        <description>
            Each caught exception type should be handled in its own catch clause.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/AbstractClassWithoutAbstractMethod">
        <description>
            The abstract class does not contain any abstract methods. An abstract class suggests
            an incomplete implementation, which is to be completed by subclasses implementing the
            abstract methods. If the class is intended to be used as a base class only (not to be instantiated
            directly) a protected constructor can be provided prevent direct instantiation.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SimplifyConditional">
        <description>
            No need to check for null before an instanceof; the instanceof keyword returns false when given a null argument.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/CompareObjectsWithEquals">
        <description>
            Use equals() to compare object references; avoid comparing them with ==.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/PositionLiteralsFirstInComparisons">
        <description>
            Position literals first in comparisons, if the second argument is null then NullPointerExceptions
            can be avoided, they will just return false.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/PositionLiteralsFirstInCaseInsensitiveComparisons">
        <description>
            Position literals first in comparisons, if the second argument is null then NullPointerExceptions
            can be avoided, they will just return false.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/UnnecessaryLocalBeforeReturn">
        <description>
            Avoid the creation of unnecessary local variables
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/multithreading.xml/NonThreadSafeSingleton">
        <description>
            Non-thread safe singletons can result in bad state changes. Eliminate
            static singletons if possible by instantiating the object directly. Static
            singletons are usually not needed as only a single instance exists anyway.
            Other possible fixes are to synchronize the entire method or to use an
            initialize-on-demand holder class (do not use the double-check idiom).

            See Effective Java, item 48.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/ConstantsInInterface">
        <description>
            An interface should be used only to characterize the external behaviour of an
            implementing class: using an interface as a container of constants is a poor
            usage pattern and not recommended.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/PreserveStackTrace">
        <description>
            Throwing a new exception from a catch block without passing the original exception into the
            new exception will cause the original stack trace to be lost making it difficult to debug
            effectively.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UseCollectionIsEmpty">
        <description>
            The isEmpty() method on java.util.Collection is provided to determine if a collection has any elements.
            Comparing the value of size() to 0 does not convey intent as well as the isEmpty() method.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/ClassWithOnlyPrivateConstructorsShouldBeFinal">
        <description>
            A class with only private constructors should be final, unless the private constructor
            is invoked by a inner class.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SingularField">
        <description>

            Fields whose scopes are limited to just single methods do not rely on the containing
            object to provide them to other methods. They may be better implemented as local variables
            within those methods.

        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/AbstractClassWithoutAnyMethod">
        <description>
            If an abstract class does not provides any methods, it may be acting as a simple data container
            that is not meant to be instantiated. In this case, it is probably better to use a private or
            protected constructor in order to prevent instantiation than make the class misleadingly abstract.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/TooFewBranchesForASwitchStatement">
        <description>
            Switch statements are indended to be used to support complex branching behaviour. Using a switch for only a few
            cases is ill-advised, since switches are not as easy to understand as if-then statements. In these cases use the
            if-then statement to increase code readability.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <!-- sometimes easier to read.  Lowering priority to warning -->
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/LogicInversion">
        <description>
            Use opposite operator instead of negating the whole expression with a logic complement operator.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/FieldDeclarationsShouldBeAtStartOfClass">
        <description>
            Fields should be declared at the top of the class, before any method declarations, constructors, initializers or inner classes.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <!-- afraid this will pick up too much existing code.  Lowering priority -->
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/GodClass">
        <description>
            The God Class rule detects the God Class design flaw using metrics. God classes do too many things,
            are very big and overly complex. They should be split apart to be more object-oriented.
            The rule uses the detection strategy described in "Object-Oriented Metrics in Practice".
            The violations are reported against the entire class. See also the references:
            Michele Lanza and Radu Marinescu. Object-Oriented Metrics in Practice:
            Using Software Metrics to Characterize, Evaluate, and Improve the Design
            of Object-Oriented Systems. Springer, Berlin, 1 edition, October 2006. Page 80.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/DuplicateImports">
        <description>
            Duplicate or overlapping import statements should be avoided.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/DontImportJavaLang">
        <description>
            Avoid importing anything from the package 'java.lang'.  These classes are automatically imported (JLS 7.5.3).
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UnusedImports">
        <description>
            Avoid the use of unused import statements to prevent unwanted dependencies.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/ImportFromSamePackage">
        <description>
            There is no need to import a type that lives in the same package.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/UnnecessaryFullyQualifiedName">
        <description>
            Import statements allow the use of non-fully qualified names.  The use of a fully qualified name
            which is covered by an import statement is redundant.  Consider using the non-fully qualified name.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UseProperClassLoader">
        <description>
            In J2EE, the getClassLoader() method might not work as expected. Use
            Thread.currentThread().getContextClassLoader() instead.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/JUnitSpelling">
        <description>
            Some JUnit framework methods are easy to misspell.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/JUnitAssertionsShouldIncludeMessage">
        <description>
            JUnit assertions should include an informative message - i.e., use the three-argument version of
            assertEquals(), not the two-argument version.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/JUnitTestsShouldIncludeAssert">
        <description>
            JUnit tests should include at least one assertion.  This makes the tests more robust, and using assert
            with messages provide the developer a clearer idea of what the test does.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/TestClassWithoutTestCases">
        <description>
            Test classes end with the suffix Test. Having a non-test class with that name is not a good practice,
            since most people will assume it is a test case. Test classes have test methods named testXXX.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UnnecessaryBooleanAssertion">
        <description>
            A JUnit test assertion with a boolean literal is unnecessary since it always will evaluate to the same thing.
            Consider using flow control (in case of assertTrue(false) or similar) or simply removing
            statements like assertTrue(true) and assertFalse(false).  If you just want a test to halt after finding
            an error, use the fail() method and provide an indication message of why it did.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UseAssertEqualsInsteadOfAssertTrue">
        <description>
            This rule detects JUnit assertions in object equality. These assertions should be made by more specific methods, like assertEquals.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UseAssertSameInsteadOfAssertTrue">
        <description>
            This rule detects JUnit assertions in object references equality. These assertions should be made
            by more specific methods, like assertSame, assertNotSame.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UseAssertNullInsteadOfAssertTrue">
        <description>
            This rule detects JUnit assertions in object references equality. These assertions should be made by
            more specific methods, like assertNull, assertNotNull.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SimplifyBooleanAssertion">
        <description>
            Avoid negation in an assertTrue or assertFalse test.

            For example, rephrase:

            assertTrue(!expr);

            as:

            assertFalse(expr);
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UseAssertTrueInsteadOfAssertEquals">
        <description>
            When asserting a value is the same as a boolean literal, use assertTrue/assertFalse, instead of assertEquals.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UseCorrectExceptionLogging">
        <description>
            To make sure the full stacktrace is printed out, use the logging statement with two arguments: a String and a Throwable.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/MoreThanOneLogger">
        <description>
            Normally only one logger is used in each class.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/SystemPrintln">
        <description>
            References to System.(out|err).print are usually intended for debugging purposes and can remain in
            the codebase even in production code. By using a logger one can enable/disable this behaviour at
            will (and by priority) and avoid clogging the Standard out log.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/AvoidPrintStackTrace">
        <description>
            Avoid printStackTrace(); use a logger call instead.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/ReplaceVectorWithList">
        <description>
            Consider replacing Vector usages with the newer java.util.ArrayList if expensive thread-safe operations are not required.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/ReplaceHashtableWithMap">
        <description>
            Consider replacing Hashtable usage with the newer java.util.Map if thread safety is not required.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/ReplaceEnumerationWithIterator">
        <description>
            Consider replacing Enumeration usages with the newer java.util.Iterator
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidEnumAsIdentifier">
        <description>
            Use of the term 'enum' will conflict with newer versions of Java since it is a reserved word.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidAssertAsIdentifier">
        <description>
            Use of the term 'assert' will conflict with newer versions of Java since it is a reserved word.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/IntegerInstantiation">
        <description>
            Calling new Integer() causes memory allocation that can be avoided by the static Integer.valueOf().
            It makes use of an internal cache that recycles earlier instances making it more memory efficient.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/ByteInstantiation">
        <description>
            Calling new Byte() causes memory allocation that can be avoided by the static Byte.valueOf().
            It makes use of an internal cache that recycles earlier instances making it more memory efficient.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/ShortInstantiation">
        <description>
            Calling new Short() causes memory allocation that can be avoided by the static Short.valueOf().
            It makes use of an internal cache that recycles earlier instances making it more memory efficient.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/LongInstantiation">
        <description>
            Calling new Long() causes memory allocation that can be avoided by the static Long.valueOf().
            It makes use of an internal cache that recycles earlier instances making it more memory efficient.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/JUnit4TestShouldUseBeforeAnnotation">
        <description>
            In JUnit 3, the setUp method was used to set up all data entities required in running tests.
            JUnit 4 skips the setUp method and executes all methods annotated with @Before before all tests
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/JUnit4TestShouldUseAfterAnnotation">
        <description>
            In JUnit 3, the tearDown method was used to clean up all data entities required in running tests.
            JUnit 4 skips the tearDown method and executes all methods annotated with @After after running each test
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/JUnit4TestShouldUseTestAnnotation">
        <description>
            In JUnit 3, the framework executed all methods which started with the word test as a unit test.
            In JUnit 4, only methods annotated with the @Test annotation are executed.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/JUnit4SuitesShouldUseSuiteAnnotation">
        <description>
            In JUnit 3, test suites are indicated by the suite() method. In JUnit 4, suites are indicated
            through the @RunWith(Suite.class) annotation.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/JUnitUseExpected">
        <description>
            In JUnit4, use the @Test(expected) annotation to denote tests that should throw exceptions.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/ShortVariable">
        <description>
            Fields, local variables, or parameter names that are very short are not helpful to the reader.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/LongVariable">
        <description>
            Fields, formal arguments, or local variable names that are too long can make the code difficult to follow.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/ShortMethodName">
        <description>
            Method names that are very short are not helpful to the reader.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/SuspiciousHashcodeMethodName">
        <description>
            The method name and return type are suspiciously close to hashCode(), which may denote an intention
            to override the hashCode() method.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <!--<rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/SuspiciousConstantFieldName">-->
        <!--<description>-->
            <!--Field names using all uppercase characters - Sun's Java naming conventions indicating constants - should-->
            <!--be declared as final.-->
        <!--</description>-->
        <!--<priority>5</priority>-->
    <!--</rule>-->

    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/SuspiciousEqualsMethodName">
        <description>
            The method name and parameter number are suspiciously close to equals(Object), which can denote an
            intention to override the equals(Object) method.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidFieldNameMatchingTypeName">
        <description>
            It is somewhat confusing to have a field name matching the declaring class name.
            This probably means that type and/or field names should be chosen more carefully.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidFieldNameMatchingMethodName">
        <description>
            It can be confusing to have a field name with the same name as a method. While this is permitted,
            having information (field) and actions (method) is not clear naming. Developers versed in
            Smalltalk often prefer this approach as the methods denote accessor methods.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/NoPackage">
        <description>
            Detects when a class or interface does not have a package definition.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/PackageCase">
        <description>
            Detects when a package definition contains uppercase characters.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <!--<rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/MIsLeadingVariableName">-->
        <!--<description>-->
            <!--Detects when a non-field has a name starting with 'm_'.  This usually denotes a field and could be confusing.-->
        <!--</description>-->
        <!--<priority>5</priority>-->
    <!--</rule>-->
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/BooleanGetMethodName">
        <description>
            Methods that return boolean results should be named as predicate statements to denote this.
            I.e, 'isReady()', 'hasValues()', 'canCommit()', 'willFail()', etc.   Avoid the use of the 'get'
            prefix for these methods.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/ShortClassName">
        <description>

            Short Classnames with fewer than e.g. five characters are not recommended.

        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/GenericsNaming">
        <description>
            Names for references to generic values should be limited to a single uppercase letter.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/UseArrayListInsteadOfVector">
        <description>
            ArrayList is a much better Collection implementation than Vector if thread-safe operation is not required.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/SimplifyStartsWith">
        <description>
            Since it passes in a literal of length 1, calls to (string).startsWith can be rewritten using (string).charAt(0)
            at the expense of some readability.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/UseStringBufferForStringAppends">
        <description>
            The use of the '+=' operator for appending strings causes the JVM to create and use an internal StringBuffer.
            If a non-trivial number of these concatenations are being used then the explicit use of a StringBuilder or
            threadsafe StringBuffer is recommended to avoid this.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/UseArraysAsList">
        <description>
            The java.util.Arrays class has a "asList" method that should be used when you want to create a new List from
            an array of objects. It is faster than executing a loop to copy all the elements of the array one by one.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/AvoidArrayLoops">
        <description>
            Instead of manually copying data between two arrays, use the efficient System.arraycopy method instead.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/UnnecessaryWrapperObjectCreation">
        <description>
            Most wrapper classes provide static conversion methods that avoid the need to create intermediate objects
            just to create the primitive forms. Using these avoids the cost of creating objects that also need to be
            garbage-collected later.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/AddEmptyString">
        <description>
            The conversion of literals to strings by concatenating them with empty strings is inefficient.
            It is much better to use one of the type-specific toString() methods instead.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/RedundantFieldInitializer">
        <description>
            Java will initialize fields with known default values so any explicit initialization of those same defaults
            is redundant and results in a larger class file (approximately three additional bytecode instructions per field).
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <!-- this is a decent optimization rule, but sometimes for readability it's better to go ahead
        and declare vars before they are needed.  If this could be suppressed for literals, would keep it still -->
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/PrematureDeclaration">
        <description>
            Checks for variables that are defined before they might be used. A reference is deemed to be premature if it is created right before a block of code that doesn't use it that also has the ability to return or throw an exception.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidCatchingThrowable">
        <description>
            Catching Throwable errors is not recommended since its scope is very broad. It includes runtime issues such as
            OutOfMemoryError that should be exposed and managed separately.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SignatureDeclareThrowsException">
        <description>
            Methods that declare the generic Exception as a possible throwable are not very helpful since their
            failure modes are unclear. Use a class derived from RuntimeException or a more specific checked exception.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/ExceptionAsFlowControl">
        <description>
            Using Exceptions as form of flow control is not recommended as they obscure true exceptions when debugging.
            Either add the necessary validation or use an alternate control structure.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidCatchingNPE">
        <description>
            Code should never throw NullPointerExceptions under normal circumstances.  A catch block may hide the
            original error, causing other, more subtle problems later on.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <!-- ideally, should do this, but too much code relys on it -->
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/AvoidThrowingRawExceptionTypes">
        <description>
            Avoid throwing certain exception types. Rather than throw a raw RuntimeException, Throwable,
            Exception, or Error, use a subclassed exception or error instead.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/AvoidThrowingNullPointerException">
        <description>
            Avoid throwing NullPointerExceptions. These are confusing because most people will assume that the
            virtual machine threw it. Consider using an IllegalArgumentException instead; this will be
            clearly seen as a programmer-initiated exception.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/AvoidRethrowingException">
        <description>
            Catch blocks that merely rethrow a caught exception only add to code size and runtime complexity.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/DoNotExtendJavaLangError">
        <description>

            Errors are system exceptions. Do not extend them.

        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/DoNotThrowExceptionInFinally">
        <description>

            Throwing exceptions within a 'finally' block is confusing since they may mask other exceptions
            or code defects.
            Note: This is a PMD implementation of the Lint4j rule "A throw in a finally block"

        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/AvoidThrowingNewInstanceOfSameException">
        <description>
            Catch blocks that merely rethrow a caught exception wrapped inside a new instance of the same type only add to
            code size and runtime complexity.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidLosingExceptionInformation">
        <description>
            Statements in a catch block that invoke accessors on the exception without using the information
            only add to code size.  Either remove the invocation, or use the return result.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/AvoidDuplicateLiterals">
        <description>
            Code containing duplicate String literals can usually be improved by declaring the String as a constant field.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/StringInstantiation">
        <description>
            Avoid instantiating String objects; this is usually unnecessary since they are immutable and can be safely shared.
        </description>
        <priority>2</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/StringToString">
        <description>
            Avoid calling toString() on objects already known to be string instances; this is unnecessary.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/InefficientStringBuffering">
        <description>
            Avoid concatenating non-literals in a StringBuffer constructor or append() since intermediate buffers will
            need to be be created and destroyed by the JVM.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UnnecessaryCaseChange">
        <description>
            Using equalsIgnoreCase() is faster than using toUpperCase/toLowerCase().equals()
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/UseStringBufferLength">
        <description>
            Use StringBuffer.length() to determine StringBuffer length rather than using StringBuffer.toString().equals("")
            or StringBuffer.toString().length() == ...
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/AppendCharacterWithChar">
        <description>
            Avoid concatenating characters as strings in StringBuffer/StringBuilder.append methods.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/ConsecutiveAppendsShouldReuse">
        <description>
            Consecutively calls to StringBuffer/StringBuilder .append should reuse the target object. This can improve the performance.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/ConsecutiveLiteralAppends">
        <description>
            Consecutively calling StringBuffer/StringBuilder.append with String literals
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/UseIndexOfChar">
        <description>
            Use String.indexOf(char) when checking for the index of a single character; it executes faster.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/InefficientEmptyStringCheck">
        <description>
            String.trim().length() is an inefficient way to check if a String is really empty, as it
            creates a new String object just to check its size. Consider creating a static function that
            loops through a string, checking Character.isWhitespace() on each character and returning
            false if a non-whitespace character is found.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/InsufficientStringBufferDeclaration">
        <description>
            Failing to pre-size a StringBuffer or StringBuilder properly could cause it to re-size many times
            during runtime. This rule attempts to determine the total number the characters that are actually
            passed into StringBuffer.append(), but represents a best guess "worst case" scenario. An empty
            StringBuffer/StringBuilder constructor initializes the object to 16 characters. This default
            is assumed if the length of the constructor can not be determined.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/performance.xml/UselessStringValueOf">
        <description>
            No need to call String.valueOf to append to a string; just use the valueOf() argument directly.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/StringBufferInstantiationWithChar">
        <description>
            Individual character values provided as initialization arguments will be converted into integers.
            This can lead to internal buffer sizes that are larger than expected. Some examples:

            new StringBuffer()      //  16
            new StringBuffer(6)     //  6
            new StringBuffer("hello world")  // 11 + 16 = 27
            new StringBuffer('A')   //  chr(A) = 65
            new StringBuffer("A")   //  1 + 16 = 17

            new StringBuilder()         //  16
            new StringBuilder(6)        //  6
            new StringBuilder("hello world")  // 11 + 16 = 27
            new StringBuilder('C')   //  chr(C) = 67
            new StringBuilder("A")   //  1 + 16 = 17
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UseEqualsToCompareStrings">
        <description>
            Using '==' or '!=' to compare strings only works if intern version is used on both sides.
            Use the equals() method instead.
        </description>
        <priority>1</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/AvoidStringBufferField">
        <description>

            StringBuffers/StringBuilders can grow considerably, and so may become a source of memory leaks
            if held within objects with long lifetimes.

        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/MethodReturnsInternalArray">
        <description>
            Exposing internal arrays to the caller violates object encapsulation since elements can be
            removed or replaced outside of the object that owns it. It is safer to return a copy of the array.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/ArrayIsStoredDirectly">
        <description>
            Constructors and methods receiving arrays should clone objects and store the copy.
            This prevents future changes from the user from affecting the original array.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/LooseCoupling">
        <description>
            Avoid using implementation types (i.e., HashSet); use the interface (i.e, Set) instead
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <!-- would like to keep this, but it breaks too many things -->
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/SignatureDeclareThrowsException">
        <description>
            It is unclear which exceptions that can be thrown from the methods.
            It might be difficult to document and understand the vague interfaces.
            Use either a class derived from RuntimeException or a checked exception.

            JUnit classes are excluded.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UnnecessaryConversionTemporary">
        <description>
            Avoid the use temporary objects when converting primitives to Strings. Use the static conversion methods
            on the wrapper classes instead.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/codestyle.xml/UnnecessaryReturn">
        <description>
            Avoid the use of unnecessary return statements.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/design.xml/UselessOverridingMethod">
        <description>
            The overriding method merely calls the same method defined in a superclass.
        </description>
        <priority>4</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UselessOperationOnImmutable">
        <description>
            An operation on an Immutable object (String, BigDecimal or BigInteger) won't change the object itself
            since the result of the operation is a new object. Therefore, ignoring the operation result is an error.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/errorprone.xml/UnusedNullCheckInEquals">
        <description>
            After checking an object reference for null, you should invoke equals() on that object rather than passing it to another object's equals() method.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UnusedPrivateField">
        <description>
            Detects when a private field is declared and/or assigned a value, but not used.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UnusedLocalVariable">
        <description>
            Detects when a local variable is declared and/or assigned, but not used.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UnusedPrivateMethod">
        <description>
            Unused Private Method detects when a private method is declared but is unused.
        </description>
        <priority>3</priority>
    </rule>
    <rule ref="category/java/bestpractices.xml/UnusedFormalParameter">
        <description>
            Avoid passing parameters to methods or constructors without actually referencing them in the method body.
        </description>
        <priority>5</priority>
    </rule>
</ruleset>
